Denwin Solomons

City of Johannesburg, Gauteng, South Africa

denwin.solomons@gmail.com

+27 66 2588 794

linkedin.com/in/denwin-solomons-24699835

Summary

The Fourth Industrial Revolution represents a fundamental change in the way we live, work and relate to one another. It is a new chapter in human development, enabled by extraordinary technology advances commensurate with those of the first, second and third industrial revolutions.

After losing my job as a travel consultant as a result of COVID-19, I knew I wanted to be a contributor to this AMAZING revolution. I started researching and came across Wethinkcode_. Wethinkcode_ offers a two year, tuition free, NQF level 5 qualification in systems development. I was fortunate enough to have been accepted to the program. In my time at here, I was exposed and learned various programming languages. These include:

- *Python
- *Java
- *Dart
- *JavaScript
- *HTML & CSS
- *SQLite (DBMS)
- *Flutter (Framework).

As a newbie to the field, I struggled in the beginning, I have since grown and came to understand programming concepts well. I am a hardworking, easy to work with individual, and always open to challenges.

Experience

Safari Travel Consultant

Jan 2018 - Aug 2020 (2 years 8 months)

Senior Reservations Consultant

Aguila Private Game Reserve

Nov 2013 - Jan 2018 (4 years 3 months)

- Managing the reservations process of bookings from quote to finalising, invoicing and travel documents
- Consistent and clear communication with agents, sales teams and preferred partners
- Professional manner of servicing agents and guests
- Proactive selling of company products and services
- Constant interaction with colleagues, agents, guests and suppliers
- In-depth knowledge of the Innkeeper reservation system, will be an advantage
- Computer literate in Microsoft Word, Excel and Outlook

Invoicing Clerk

ScentPac CC

Apr 2013 - Oct 2013 (7 months)

- # Perform complex clerical and entry-level accounts receivable activities.
- # Compiles data from field service tickets, freight tickets, sales quotes and supporting documents to verify accuracy of billing data using calculator and computer.
- # Compute and record charges, cost of lost or damaged goods, freight charges, rentals, and similar items.
- # Compare print-outs against source documents to verify accuracy and to reconcile errors.
- # Periodically review records and subsequent computer printouts to aid in balancing accounts and to identify suspense items or delinquent accounts requiring further action.
- # File and maintain clerical records, and reports pertinent information to accounting and bookkeeping.
- # Prepare and mail bills or statements.
- # May proofread and post operations progress or other reports and make a monthly summary or recap of such reports as needed.
- # Type invoices, account statements, reports, and other records.
- # Personally observe safety and security procedures and proper use of equipment and material.
- Actively promote safety process and report any safety issues to proper channels for action.

Education



WeThinkCode

Dip. (Systems Development), Computer Software Engineering Sep 2021 - Feb 2023

Skills

Flutter • Dart • SQL • Python (Programming Language) • Java • Communication • Customer Service • Microsoft Word • Outlook • Teamwork